Guide to the Allegheny County, Pa. Coroner's Office Records, 1884-1976 AIS.1982.07
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Coroner Case Files, I.
  - Coroner Case Files, 1887-1973; 1.
    - Docket Range 192206-155 through 192207-179 (Box 328)
    - Docket Range 192207-180 through 192208-251 (Box 329)
    - Docket Range 192208-252 through 192210-6 (Box 330)
    - Docket Range 192210-7 through 192211-30 (Box 331)
    - Docket Range 192211-31 through 192212-135 (Box 332)
    - Docket Range 192212-136 through 192301-165 (Box 333)
    - Docket Range 192301-166 through 192302-226 (Box 334)
    - Docket Range 192302-227 through 192303-228 (Box 335)
    - Docket Range 192303-229 through 192304-250 (Box 336)
    - Docket Range 192304-251 through 192305-263 (Box 337)
    - Docket Range 19305-264 through 192307-46 (Box 338)
    - Docket Range 192307-47 through 192308-30 (Box 339)
    - Docket Range 192308-31 through 192309-28 (Box 340)
    - Docket Range 192309-29 through 192310-70 (Box 341)
    - Docket Range 192310-71 through 192311-35 (Box 342)
    - Docket Range 192311-36 through 192312-60 (Box 343)
    - Docket Range 192312-61 through 192401-48 (Box 344)
    - Docket Range 192401-49 through 192401-316 (Box 345)
    - Docket Range 192401-317 through 192402-274 (Box 346)
    - Docket Range 192402-275 through 192403-290 (Box 347)
    - Docket Range 192403-291 through 192404-235 (Box 348)
    - Docket Range 192404-236 through 192405-220 (Box 349)
    - Docket Range 192405-221 through 192406-210 (Box 350)
    - Docket Range 192406-211 through 192407-217 (Box 351)
    - Docket Range 192407-218 through 192408-232 (Box 352)
    - Docket Range 192408-233 through 192409-208 (Box 353)
    - Docket Range 192409-209 through 192410-265 (Box 354)
    - Docket Range 192410-266 through 192412-3 (Box 355)
    - Docket Range 192412-4 through 192501-70 (Box 356)
    - Docket Range 192501-71 through 192502-110 (Box 357)
    - Docket Range 192502-111 through 192503-127 (Box 358)
    - Docket Range 192503-128 through 192504-142 (Box 359)
    - Docket Range 192504-143 through 192505-128 (Box 360)
    - Docket Range 192505-129 through 192506-108 (Box 361)
    - Docket Range 192506-109 through 192507-150 (Box 362)
    - Docket Range 192507-151 through 192508-194 (Box 363)
    - Docket Range 192508-195 through 192509-249 (Box 364)
    - Docket Range 192509-250 through 192510-237 (Box 365)
    - Docket Range 192510-238 through 192512-95 (Box 366)
    - Docket Range 192512-96 through 192601-100 (Box 367)
    - Docket Range 192601-101 through 192602-91 (Box 368)
    - Docket Range 192602-92 through 192603-114 (Box 369)
    - Docket Range 192603-93 through 192604-57 (Box 370)
    - Docket Range 192604-58 through 192605-64 (Box 371)
    - Docket Range 192605-65 through 192606-94 (Box 372)
    - Docket Range 192606-95 through 192607-147 (Box 373)
    - Docket Range 192607-148 through 192608-172 (Box 374)
    - Docket Range 192608-173 through 192609-199 (Box 375)
    - Docket Range 192609-200 through 192610-237 (Box 376)
    - Docket Range 192610-238 through 192611-240 (Box 377)
    - Docket Range 192611-241 through 192612-254 (Box 378)
    - Docket Range 192612-255 through 192701-238 (Box 379)
    - Docket Range 192701-239 through 192702-128 (Box 380)
    - Docket Range 192702-129 through 192703-64 (Box 381)
    - Docket Range 192703-65 through 192704-205 (Box 382)
    - Docket Range 192703-206 through 192704-238 (Box 383)
    - Docket Range 192704-239 through 192705-195 (Box 384)
    - Docket Range 192705-196 through 192706-175 (Box 385)
    - Docket Range 192706-176 through 192707-139 (Box 386)
    - Docket Range 192707-140 through 192708-105 (Box 387)
    - Docket Range 192708-106 through 192709-156 (Box 388)
    - Docket Range 192709-157 through 192710-200 (Box 389)
    - Docket Range 192710-201 through 192711-213 (Box 390)
    - Docket Range 192711-214 through 192712-195 (Box 391)
    - Docket Range 192712-196 through 192801-177 (Box 392)
    - Docket Range 192801-178 through 192802-103 (Box 393)
    - Docket Range 192802-104 through 192803-125 (Box 394)
    - Docket Range 192803-126 through 192804-120 (Box 395)
    - Docket Range 192804-121 through 192805-183 (Box 396)
    - Docket Range 192805-184 through 192806-184 (Box 397)
    - Docket Range 192806-185 through 192807-186 (Box 398)
    - Docket Range 192807-187 through 192808-218 (Box 399)
    - Docket Range 192808-219 through 192809-194 (Box 400)
    - Docket Range 192809-195 through 192810-202 (Box 401)
    - Docket Range 192810-203 through 192811-212 (Box 402)
    - Docket Range 192811-213 through 192812-249 (Box 403)
    - Docket Range 192812-250 through 192901-251 (Box 404)
    - Docket Range 192901-252 through 192902-185 (Box 405)
    - Docket Range 192902-186 through 192903-151 (Box 406)
    - Docket Range 192903-152 through 192904-112 (Box 407)
    - Docket Range 192904-113 through 192905-147 (Box 408)
    - Docket Range 192905-148 through 192906-142 (Box 409)
    - Docket Range 192906-143 through 192907-129 (Box 410)
    - Docket Range 192907-130 through 192908-180 (Box 411)
    - Docket Range 192909-169 through 192910-189 (Box 413)
    - Docket Range 192910-190 through 192911-171 (Box 414)
    - Docket Range 192911-172 through 192912-173 (Box 415)
    - Docket Range 192912-174 through 193001-110 (Box 416)
    - Docket Range 193001-111 through 193002-77 (Box 417)
    - Docket Range 193002-78 through 193003-91 (Box 418)
    - Docket Range 193003-92 through 193004-65 (Box 419)
    - Docket Range 193004-66 through 193005-105 (Box 420)
    - Docket Range 193005-106 through 193006-123 (Box 421)
    - Docket Range 193006-124 through 193007-117 (Box 422)
    - Docket Range 193007-118 through 193008-139 (Box 423)
    - Docket Range 193008-140 through 193009-168 (Box 424)
    - Docket Range 193009-169 through 193010-184 (Box 425)
    - Docket Range 193010-185 through 193011-169 (Box 426)
    - Docket Range 193011-170 through 193012-183 (Box 427)
    - Docket Range 193012-184 through 193101-160 (Box 428)
    - Docket Range 193101-161 through 193102-109 (Box 429)
    - Docket Range 193102-110 through 193103-127 (Box 430)
    - Docket Range 193103-128 through 193104-85 (Box 431)
    - Docket Range 193104-86 through 193105-90 (Box 432)
    - Docket Range 193105-91 through 193106-74 (Box 433)
    - Docket Range 193106-75 through 193107-77 (Box 434)
    - Docket Range 193107-78 through 193108-64 (Box 435)
    - Docket Range 193108-65 through 193109-008 (Box 436)
    - Docket Range 193109-009 through 193110-13 (Box 437)
    - Docket Range 193110-14 through 193111-9 (Box 438)
    - Docket Range 193111-10 through 193111-250 (Box 439)
    - Docket Range 193111-251 through 193112-230 (Box 440)
    - Docket Range 193112-231 through 193201-192 (Box 441)
    - Docket Range 193201-193 through 193202-170 (Box 442)
    - Docket Range 193202-171 through 193203-181 (Box 443)
    - Docket Range 193203-182 through 193204-145 (Box 444)
    - Docket Range 193204-146 through 193205-143 (Box 445)
    - Docket Range 193205-144 through 193206-150 (Box 446)
    - Docket Range 193206-151 through 193207-155 (Box 447)
    - Docket Range 193207-156 through 193208-126 (Box 448)
    - Docket Range 193208-127 through 193209-94 (Box 449)
    - Docket Range 193209-95 through 193210-84 (Box 450)
    - Docket Range 193210-85 through 193211-65 (Box 451)
    - Docket Range 193211-66 through 193212-10 (Box 452)
    - Docket Range 193212-11 through 193212-245 (Box 453)
    - Docket Range 193212-246 through 193301-175 (Box 454)
    - Docket Range 193301-176 through 193307-49 (Box 455)
    - Docket Range 193307-50 through 193308-89 (Box 456)
    - Docket Range 193308-90 through 193309-78 (Box 457)
    - Docket Range 193309-79 through 193310-91 (Box 458)
    - Docket Range 193310-92 through 193311-134 (Box 459)
    - Docket Range 193311-135 through 193312-168 (Box 460)
    - Docket Range 193312-169 through 193901-157 (Box 461)
    - Docket Range 193901-158 through 193902-135 (Box 462)
    - Docket Range 193902-136 through 193903-127 (Box 463)
    - Docket Range 193903-128 through 193904-128 (Box 464)
    - Docket Range 193904-129 through 193905-155 (Box 465)
    - Docket Range 193905-156 through 193906-146 (Box 466)
    - Docket Range 193906-147 through 193907-137 (Box 467)
    - Docket Range 193907-138 through 193908-172 (Box 468)
    - Docket Range 193908-173 through 193910-28 (Box 469)
    - Docket Range 193910-29 through 193911-10 (Box 470)
    - Docket Range 193911-11 through 193912-23 (Box 471)
    - Docket Range 193912-24 through 193912-270 (Box 472)
    - Docket Range 193912-271 through 194001-263 (Box 473)
    - Docket Range 194001-264 through 194002-230 (Box 474)
    - Docket Range 194002-231 through 194003-231 (Box 475)
    - Docket Range 194003-232 through 194005-12 (Box 476)
    - Docket Range 194005-13 through 194006-14 (Box 477)
    - Docket Range 194006-15 through 194007-40 (Box 478)
    - Docket Range 194008-41 through 194008-44 (Box 479)
    - Docket Range 194008-45 through 194009-97 (Box 480)
    - Docket Range 194009-98 through 194010-161 (Box 481)
    - Docket Range 194010-162 through 194011-164 (Box 482)
    - Docket Range 194011-165 through 194012-222 (Box 483)
    - Docket Range 194012-223 through 194101-206 (Box 484)
    - Docket Range 194101-207 through 194102-201 (Box 485)
    - Docket Range 194102-202 through 194103-202 (Box 486)
    - Docket Range 194103-203 through 194104-191 (Box 487)
    - Docket Range 194104-192 through 194105-181 (Box 488)
    - Docket Range 194105-182 through 194106-168 (Box 489)
    - Docket Range 194106-169 through 194107-192 (Box 490)
    - Docket Range 194107-193 through 194108-202 (Box 491)
    - Docket Range 194108-203 through 194109-166 (Box 492)
  - Notable Case Files, 2.
    This subseries features some of the notable case files found within the collection that have been digitized and are now available online.
    - Homestead Steel Strike, 1892
      These are the inquest files for the seven steelworkers and three Pinkerton guards that succumbed to injuries sustained during the Homestead Steel Strike of 1892. In addition to a Press Report incident summary, Proof of Identity affidavit, and jury verdict for each case there are also witness lists and several pages of witness testimony. In each case the blame is placed on an "unlawful assembly" of locked out steelworkers.
      - Witness Lists (Box 16a, Folder 1)
      - John T. McCurry Testimony, July 8, 1892 (Box 16a, Folder 2)
      - Witness Summons and Testimony, July 9-12, 1892 (Box 16a, Folder 3)
      - Witness Testimony, July 26, 1892 (Box 16a, Folder 4)
      - Witness Testimony, August 2, 1892 (Box 16a, Folder 5)
      - Charge to the Jury (Box 16a, Folder 6)
      - Joseph Sotak, a.k.a. Soppa, Steelworker, File 189208_159 (Box 16a, Folder 7)
      - John E. Morris, Steelworker, File 189208_160 (Box 16a, Folder 8)
      - Silas Wain, Steelworker, File 189208_161 (Box 16a, Folder 9)
      - Thomas Weldon, Steelworker, File 189208_162 (Box 16a, Folder 10)
      - Henry Striegel, Steelworker, File 189208_163 (Box 16a, Folder 11)
      - George W. Rutter, Steelworker, File 189208_165 (Box 16a, Folder 12)
      - Peter Farris, Steelworker, File 189208_167 (Box 16a, Folder 13)
      - Telegrams to Coroner Regarding the Shipment and Identification of Killed Pinkerton Guards, July 6-7, 1892 (Box 16a, Folder 14)
      - Thomas "T.J." Connors, Pinkerton Guard, 189208_166 (Box 16a, Folder 15)
      - J.W. Klein, Pinkerton Guard, 189208_158 (Box 16a, Folder 16)
      - Edward A.R. Spear, Pinkerton Guard, 189208_169 (Box 16a, Folder 17)
    - Victims of Jack and Ed Biddle, 1901
      These inquest files document the investigation of two murders attributed to Jack and Ed Biddle. The file of Thomas Kahney includes testimony that recounts the Biddle brothers' robbery attempt and the victim's death. Patrick Fitzgerald's file includes testimony that details the attempt to arrest the brothers. The Biddles later became part of local lore when the wife of Allegheny County Jail's warden, Kate Soffel, helped them escape and fled with the fugitives. Police caught up to the group and both brothers were fatally injured in a shootout, succumbing to their wounds in a Butler jail cell on February 1, 1902.
      - Thomas Kahney, 190103_404 (Box 67, Folder 21)
      - Patrick Fitzgerald, 190103_405 (Box 67, Folder 22)
    - Harwick Mine Disaster, 1904
      - Selwyn M. Taylor, 190404_314, January 26 - April 25, 1904 (Box 104)
      - Daniel Lysle, 190404_315, January 26 - April 25, 1904 (Box 104)
- Morgue Reports, II.
  The files do not cover all cases received at the public morgue; however some cases are documented from the following years: 1901-1902, 1911-1921, and 1928-1941. Each report contains the following information about the deceased received at the public morgue: the date received, the time received, the deceased's name, sex, color, age, residence, where they were found, who found them, articles (coffin) ordered and where it was ordered from, which undertaker the body was delivered to and which county each body is buried in and when, along with the grave number.
  - Morgue Reports, January 1901-June 1901 (Box 871)
  - Morgue Reports, July 1901-December 1901 (Box 871)
  - Morgue Reports, January 1902-June 1902 (Box 871)
  - Morgue Reports, July 1902-December 1902 (Box 871)
  - Morgue Reports, January 1911-June 1911 (Box 871)
  - Morgue Reports, July 1911-December 1911 (Box 872)
  - Morgue Reports, January 1912-June 1912 (Box 872)
  - Morgue Reports, July 1912-December 1912 (Box 872)
  - Morgue Reports, January 1913-June 1913 (Box 872)
  - Morgue Reports, July 1913-December 1913 (Box 872)
  - Morgue Reports, January 1914-June 1914 (Box 873)
  - Morgue Reports, July 1914-December 1914 (Box 873)
  - Morgue Reports, January 1915-June 1915 (Box 873)
  - Morgue Reports, July 1915-December 1915 (Box 873)
  - Morgue Reports, January 1916-June 1916 (Box 873)
  - Morgue Reports, July 1916-December 1916 (Box 873)
  - Morgue Reports, January 1917-June 1917 (Box 874)
  - Morgue Reports, July 1917-December 1917 (Box 874)
  - Morgue Reports, January 1918-June 1918 (Box 874)
  - Morgue Reports, July 1918-December 1918 (Box 874)
  - Morgue Reports, January 1919-June 1919 (Box 874)
  - Morgue Reports, July 1919-December 1919 (Box 875)
  - Morgue Reports, January 1920-June 1920 (Box 875)
  - Morgue Reports, July 1920-December 1920 (Box 875)
  - Morgue Reports, January 1921-June 1921 (Box 875)
  - Morgue Reports, July 1921-December 1921 (Box 875)
  - Morgue Reports, January 1928-June 1928 (Box 875)
  - Morgue Reports, July 1928-December 1928 (Box 875)
  - Morgue Reports, January 1929-June 1929 (Box 875)
  - Morgue Reports, July 1929-December 1929 (Box 875)
  - Morgue Reports, January 1930-June 1930 (Box 876)
  - Morgue Reports, July 1930-December 1930 (Box 876)
  - Morgue Reports, January 1931-June 1931 (Box 876)
  - Morgue Reports, July 1931-December 1931 (Box 876)
  - Morgue Reports, January 1934-June 1934 (Box 876)
  - Morgue Reports, July 1934-December 1934 (Box 876)
  - Morgue Reports, January 1937-June 1937 (Box 877)
  - Morgue Reports, July 1937-December 1937 (Box 877)
  - Morgue Reports, January 1938-June 1938 (Box 877)
  - Morgue Reports, July 1938-December 1938 (Box 877)
  - Morgue Reports, January 1939-June 1939 (Box 877)
  - Morgue Reports, July 1939-December 1939 (Box 877)
  - Morgue Reports, July 1940- February 1941 (Box 877)
- Administrative Records, III.
  A small amount of administrative files generated by the Coroner's Office contain some information on particular investigations. The files are arranged in one box, in the order in which they were found. Each folder is clearly marked and the information in these folders covers the entire time period from 1884 to 1976.
  - Scraps from case files in Box 1 of the Coroner Case Files, 1887 (Box 870, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous case files, 1884 - 1934 (Box 870, Folder 2)
  - Statement of Deaths, January 1887 (Box 870, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1893 (Box 870, Folder 4)
  - County Contract with Monaghan Brothers, 1926 (Box 870, Folder 5)
  - Clinical Diabetes Association, Dr. Mirsky, February 1956 (Box 870, Folder 6)
  - Commissioner's Meeting, January 4, 1960 (Box 870, Folder 7)
  - Employment Applications, 1968 (Box 870, Folder 8)
  - Latshaw Papers: Stenographer, 1953-1956 (Box 870, Folder 9)
  - Albert Goodman Misc. Papers, 1954-1955 (Box 870, Folder 10)
  - Gregory A. Mill Accident: Note and Photos only, 1975 (Box 870, Folder 11)
  - Raymond M. Carrol, 1976 (Box 870, Folder 12)
  - Edward Schaffer, unknown (Box 870, Folder 13)